ALEXIS SUÁREZ

SR FULL STACK DEVELOPER

alesuarezaliano@gmail.com - +598 98 985 709 - linkedin - Github

I started in the world of programming nearly 11 years ago when I began studying Computer Engineering. I'm more oriented to the frontend, but in most of my jobs I'm also part of the backend development. I'm a self-taught, responsible, and hardworking professional who is constantly learning. Recently, I've been particularly focused on emerging technologies, especially AI, which has enhanced my productivity as a developer and opened new paths for growth. This expertise allows me to quickly develop complex features with high efficiency.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Sr Frontend Developer. - D24 - Eron International

Apr 2023 - Present

Eron is a fintech that provides an end-to-end solution for billing and payment processes. As a Senior Developer, I am accustomed to being part of the entire ticket flow, from its creation and discussions with PO through development to deployment. I'm part of the credit card team. I developed features related to installment configurations, anticipation fees, and user data across different projects. I've also created SDKs to enable seamless client integration with the payment gateway, and developed component libraries to enhance efficiency and consistency across projects.

Semi Senior Full Stack Developer. - Merov (startup)

Mar 2022 - Apr 2023

Merov is a multi-currency marketplace where I work as a full-stack developer. I developed the first version of the web platform and subsequently took charge of developing the back office to manage administrative actions. While overseeing the back office, I continue to develop new features for the web platform and assist with backend. development.

Semi Senior Frontend Developer - Freelance. - Goldfarb

Sep 2023 - Nov 2023

Goldfarb is a marketplace for work tools. I developed a flexible promotion system using encapsulated and reusable components, facilitating easy addition of new promotion types. Additionally, I contributed to bug fixing and overall marketplace improvement.

Jr Full Stack Developer - Código del Sur

Dec 2021 - Mar 2022

I developed enterprise back office features for employee data management, enabling efficient input, retrieval, and display of workforce information.

Jr Full Stack Developer - Arnaldo Castro

Dec 2020 - Dec 2021

I worked in R&D, developing features for IoT solutions. My focus was on creating scalable software components for integrating and managing IoT devices and data streams.

MAIN STACK

 Next React

Vite

Typescript

Tailwind

- Al
- Nest
- Node
- Prisma
- MySQL
- Redux
- GraphQL
- Zustand
- Git
- Jest

- Auth0
- AWS
- NewRelic
- Docker
- Scrum
- Nexus
- Kanban
- Vercel
- Storybook
- CI/CD

EDUCATION

Styled Component

- Systems Engineering **ORT University** 2019-now
- UDELAR Computer Engineering 2014-2018

REFERENCES

- Eng. Nicolas Saúl Merov CTO
 - +598 99 365 928
- Eng. Steffano Chilotte Fron TL
 - +598 98 805 254

LANGUAGE

- Spanish · native
- English · advanced Currently taking private lessons